ANDRIN FASSBIND

Junior Software Engineer

\$\subset\$ +41 79 964 8961 @ andrin.fassbind@gmail.com @ andrinfassbind.ch Zurich



SUMMARY

Passionate and ambitious there is usually not a single day when I don't want to learn something new. Throughout my Bachelor's Degree, I honed my expertise in Machine Learning, Cloud Computing and Secure Development alongside core Computer Science principles. In my spare time I'm currently learning about developing frontend animations and learn about Event Sourcing Patterns. I also like to use Docker. If I were to launch a Startup my Backend would be implemented in Spring Boot. You are welcome to explore my personal portfolio website.

IT EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Intern

Ergon Informatik



- Migration and development for a fintech application used by more than 100'000 Customers to manage their Investment Portfolios (6 Months)
- Development and bug fixing for one of the biggest medical healthcare application for the Swiss market (6 Months)
- · Implementing intuitive and reusable frontend components using Angular with Typescript
- Implementing scalable backend using Java EE with Kotlin
- SQL migrations
- Requirements Engineering with the client and QA

Full Stack Developer

Silias

- Software Architecture & Software Development Client/Server Application for approx. 50-100 Users
- · Requirements Engineering in close cooperation with the client
- Design and Development of UI using Next.js Typescript
- · Design and Development of Backend using Next.js and Node.js
- Design and Development of SQL Database
- · Core features are: personalized timetables, lessons purchasing and paying using Stripe API, File Sharing Service 10 Gb per User

OTHER JOB EXPERIENCE

Nurse (Temporary Contract)

Seniorenzentrum Wiesengrund

= 02/2021 - 08/2021

During Covid I was able to support a station of 30 residents as a nurse. In the team I was guiding noncertified Nurse Assistants as well.

Cabin Crew

Swiss International Air Lines

= 01/2019 - 08/2020

On long-hault and short-hault flights I served international customers in english and german and visited many countries all around the globe. Being able to work in different teams from different backgrounds a d nationalities enhanced my team working abilities.

Sergeant (militia)

Swiss Armed Forces

= 07/2017 - 05/2018

My main task was to educate up to 30 recruits in their basic training. I was responsible for structuring the learning units and teaching them.

Nurse (Temporary Contract)

Pflegezentrum Abendruh

m 06/2016

My main task was supporting a nursing station of 15 residents suffering from physical and or psychological diseases.

COMPETENCE



Software Development Lifecycle

The Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science at ZHAW School of Engineering has a strong focus on Software Development. Therefore, I was able to achieve a strong theoretical foundation in OOP, Software Design and Secure Development Lifecycles as well as Clean Code standards. To round it all up I also attendant Cloud Computing lectures.



Teamplayer and Communication

Besides the technical knowledge one of the key understanding was that working in an agile team structure with good communication is crucial and makes development more efficient, less errorprone and leads to overall better coding quality. But good communication is also something I have practiced while I was working as a Cabin Crew Member and as a Nurse.



Going the extra Mile

A term I have learned while I was working as a Cabin Crew Member at Swiss meaning that it is desired to pick one or two passengers per flight and surprise them by putting in some extra effort during the service. But this is a characteristic I toke by heart in various situations so far. During the military service I agreed to be promoted as a sergeant that led to more days of service and responsibility. During my studies my goal was not only to pass the exams I was eager to achieve good grades because I wanted to benefit from my studies as much as possible. This mindset convinced fellow students who have an IT Startup (Silias) to employ me for their first software project on behalf of an external client.

SKILLS

Kotli	n Ty	pescript	Python	SQL
R Java JavaScript				
Angular Spring ReactJS/NextJS				
ExpressJS Pytorch				
Kubernetes Docker Git				

Prosodic Feature Modelling in Transformers for Speaker Verification (Bachelor Thesis)

This research aims to find out if Transformer Neural Networks and autoregressive training approaches forces the network to learn dynamic voice features.

- Pytorch to build and train Neural Networks on Speaker Verification Tasks
- Access and working with the Linux Server GPU Cluster of the Center of Artificial Intelligence at ZHAW SoE
- Docker to isolate the environment from other experiments running on the same Server
- · Github for Backup and version control

CodeMate

Design and develop an Al-powered chat application following the MVC architecture, aimed at aiding students with programming-related questions.

- The Application is written in Python
- · OpenAl API to allow interactiv chat functionality
- File System Storage using JSON
- · Github for Backup and version control

Diabetes Prediction

A group of 5 Students including me wanted to find out what factors can cause Diabetes Typ 1/2.

- Preprocess dataset containing 100'000 samples with 8 features in R
- Training and Evaluating 3 Binary Classification Models in R: Decision Tree, Logistic Regression, K-nearest-neighbours

Auto-Battler

Design and develop a Java based MVC Application in a team of 4 Students including me. The idea of the Application is a game where the user can strategically place game units on a grid board. The game units will then fight autonomously against the game units placed by the NPC.

- Implementing the MVC pattern using JavaFX library
- Config Data and player progress is persisted using File System Storage
- Heuristics for the game unit agent are based on the distance to enemy units, skills of the units and previously made decisions.

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Computer Science (Avg. Score 5.25/6.00)

ZHAW School of Engineering

= 09/2021 - 07/2024

Studies in Energy and Environmental Engineering (1. Semester)

ZHAW School of Engineering

= 09/2020 - 02/2021

Berufsmaturität

AKAD

= 02/2015 - 02/2016

Fachmann Gesundheit EFZ

Careum / Stadtspital Waid

= 08/2011 - 09/2014